Bronwyn? You here?
I can't find my keys.
Why is he still here?
Where's Sylvia?
I don't know.
Been trying
to reach her all morning.
- Has he eaten?
- Uh, I ordered us some coffees
from Balthazar
and I got him an eggs Benedict.
- He wouldn't touch it.
- All right.
- Hmm.
Hey, Bash? Bud?
Hey, can you, um,
can you try the bread?
I don't like that.
- Why not?
- It's bland.
What-- Do you want me to put
something on it for you?
Spicy curry mango?
What?
- Yeah? Okay.
Keep eating, please.
Mm.
Oh, my God.
Oh. How is that "slight pepper"?
- Could you take him?
I have to help Simon prep
a presentation before 9:00.
I-- No, I... Oh, shit,
that stuff is really spicy.
Oh, my God.
- Fine. I already missed yoga.
Mm.
Hello?
- Hey, Bash.
- Yes?
I'll take you to school today.
Really?
Uh-huh.
Eat, Bash.
- Of course.
- What is it?
Of course.
- Sylvia died.
W-What, what happened? How?
They don't know.
Mom, where's Sylvia?
Oh, honey, I already told you,
she is not gonna make it today.
Is she gonna pick me up?
No, honey, Mommy or Daddy
will pick you up.
But I want Sylvia.
I know, honey.
Are you sad because you missed
your yoga class?
Do you need an ocean breath?
Oh, honey.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Hugs.
- Mommy?
- Yes, Bash?
Sylvia walks me to my class.
Oh. Okay.
Hey, how was your day?
Mm, it was okay.
How was yours?
- Fine, under the circumstances.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, I gave
the doorman that envelope
that was addressed to Sylvia.
Told him return it to sender.
He said he has no idea
who left it at our door.
- Strange.
- It's weird, right?
How's Sebastian doing?
Good. Playing with that
coding thing you got him.
Hey, you know,
his teacher asked me
why we weren't at family
picture day, in front of him.
What? I mean, we couldn't have
been the only parents.
Right? I mean, seriously.
It was ridiculous.
So...
...how do you want to
tell Bash
Yeah, yeah, I was thinking
about that, too. Um...
Do we want to tell him?
Absolutely.
I mean, we don't want
to lie to him.
She was a really big part
of his life.
If we don't say anything,
he's gonna think death
is a bad thing.
Well, it isn't the best thing.
What did Dr. Lipschitz say
about teachable moments?
You remember?
Yeah, okay, I'll see you soon.
All right. Bye.
Bye.
- Hey, Bash.
- Hey.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Hey, buddy.
- What you playing?
- Wow.
Look at this.
What's this one?
That... This is a Kosmocertops.
- Whoa. I love it.
- Wow.
So cool.
Hey, Bash.
You remember that old dog
- we used to have
when you were...
- Mm, no. Mm-mm, mm-mm.
Well...
you really love dinosaurs,
don't you, Bash?
Uh, did you know
that some things go extinct...
- Yeah.
- ...like dinosaurs
and woolly mammoths.
Like, a meteor hit them?
- Maybe.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah. Maybe.
Or sometimes,
they... might fall asleep
and not wake up.
Can that happen to me?
- No. Mm-mm. No way.
- No. No.
That only happens
when you're really old.
Can that happen to you?
- No. No, no, no, no.
- No, no, no. No.
But you're both old.
Sylvia died.
Can she come back
and say goodbye
and then go back to being dead?
I don't think so, Bash.
But sometimes, when people die,
they have a special ceremony
to celebrate their life,
and it's called a funeral.
Can we go to there?
- We can...
- Maybe. Maybe.
Me and Daddy just need
to talk about it first.
O-Okay?
Maybe it's that foam roller?
I'll check.
- Mm-hmm.
- Where did she go?
Oh...
Nobody knows, baby.
Maybe Sylvia went back
to Trinidad and Tobago.
I just never realized
how many things
she had lying around the house.
I mean, bags...
...wigs, dresses.
We'll contact her family.
We should've hired
somebody younger.
Yeah, you know, hon?
I think we should take him.
No, that-- It is,
it is too jarring for a kid
- in kindergarten.
- Okay, listen.
I thought about it.
I think this could be
a real teachable moment.
I mean, he said
he wanted to see her.
- I think we should
honor his wishes.
You know, I was reading about
how we as Americans
have commodified death
to the point
where it's become this, like,
foreign, scary thing.
I mean, it used to be
that the living room--
the living room, in your house--
used to be the death room.
I mean, it's where you would
house the body
of the dead person and people
would come and go for days
just to, just to look
at-at the dead person.
Ew.
I'm gonna call her phone.
Maybe we can return these things
to her family in person.
I think her daughter said
the service starts at 10:00 a.m.
I don't know.
It was hard to understand her.
Maybe this next person
can be a bit more...
metropolitan.
Mm-hmm.
Sounds expensive.
Sylvia wasn't cheap.
No. Sylvia wasn't expensive.
Babe, you know
what would be so great?
- Hmm?
- If Sebastian
could become fluent in Mandarin.
Look, you know how hard it is to
find a Chinese nanny right now.
Why? No, you're just not asking
the right people.
You don't know where to look.
If you want him to be
in business, he needs to learn
the language of busin--
I'm scared.
Oh, you were so quiet,
Sebastian.
I didn't, I didn't
see you, baby.
Sylvia sits in my room
when I'm scared.
Sometimes she rubs my back.
In a circle.
And then, she sits
in the rocking chair and sings
the "Sweet T and T" song.
What?
Oh, um, well,
I don't know that song.
But I do know...
We're all here
and we are all safe.
So you don't have to worry.
I feel worried.
Well, that is okay.
You okay, Bash?
Yep. We are out there.
Hmm. Practically in the islands.
Hi, guys. Hi.
Uh, we're looking
for Sylvia Hosannah's funeral.
Is it... Is this it?
- Are you Miles?
- I am.
Yeah, we met on the phone.
I'm Khadija.
- Sylvia's daughter.
- Oh, really nice to meet you.
- Our condolences.
- Thank you so much.
She was so much a part
of our son's life.
- Oh, I know.
- Yeah.
You know, we-we have
some of her belongings here
from our apartment.
- We want to make sure
we get those to you today.
- Oh.
Oh, yeah.
Great, thank you so much.
Cockroach.
Richard. Stop it.
Trust me, it's not
as bad as it sounds.
"Cockroach has no place
at fowl party."
A'A, and I bet you know
what that means.
- You must be Sebastian.
Mommy used to call you
her little curry mouth
because you love her roti
and ate it plenty.
I heard so much
about you, all of you.
So all are staying
for the wake later, right?
Yes, we is family now, and you
have to stay for the wake later.
Right? And you'll have
plenty food.
It will have pelau, corn soup,
fish broth, doubles, roti.
And as Mommy used to say,
it's better belly bust...
...than good food waste.
- You know me heart.
- A'A.
- But it's a little
Trini all here?
- Wow...
- Oh, my gosh.
Thank you so much, Sebastian.
You made me laugh today.
- Thank you.
- That's great.
Um, so c-- am I okay here?
- Can I pull...
- Oh, just follow me,
I'll show you where to park.
- Oh, I'll take Sebastian out
and wait for you.
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Great.
Um...
Am I gonna be able to, uh,
like, get out of here?
Oh, yeah, yeah, just rest
the car keys on the hood
and Richie will
take care of you.
- Oh, okay.
- Mm-hmm. Richie.
All right. Okay.
Hi, Richie.
- Hi... Okay.
- It's fine. It's fine.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. I'm good, thanks.
Okay. Hey.
Take my hand.
I'm gonna lift you up
so you can see, okay?
Okay?
Good job, buddy.
Let's go find a seat.
Excuse me. Can we take these?
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- You sit here.
I'll sit next to you.
Good job, bud.
Hey, y'all must be the Warners.
Sylvia did love your family.
She really did.
I'm glad you're all here.
My condolences and thank you.
You're her brother?
Nah, her comparé.
Oh.
My name is Devon.
Now, if you guys
are in the market
for a new childcare service,
I'd like to offer my assistance.
I-I've been
a Little League coach,
spiritual therapist
and I install televisions
when I can.
- Wow.
- Just hit my line.
You don't have shame?
Know your place.
Hey. Psst.
My name's Curtis.
Hi. Miles. Hi.
Uh, this is my wife and son.
Yeah, man, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
So, how you know Sylvia?
Well, Sylvia used
to care for Sebastian.
Oh, serious?
You know, Sylvia was
my babysitter, too. Ha.
- Wow.
- Yeah, it's a sad day.
- But she'd be happy
we're all here, you know.
- Yeah.
So, um, you grow up in Trinidad?
Or Jamaica?
No, it's Trinidad and Tobago.
And no.
I'm from Tribeca.
Oh. Your-your accent
is so... strong.
Yeah, everyone says that.
Sorry I'm late.
As they say,
any time is Trini time, eh?
- Let the church say "amen."
Amen.
Welcome to the homegoing service
of the beloved
Sylvia Lucille Hosannah.
Bow your head
and close your eyes.
Psalm 34:18 says,
"God is close
to the brokenhearted...
- Yes.
- ...and loves those
who are crushed in spirit."
- Yes.
- That mean,
even if you may not
feel his presence,
the Lord is close to you.
- Yes.
- Yes, Lord.
And if the Lord is close to you,
Sylvia is close to you, amen?
- Amen.
- Let the church say amen, amen?
- Let me just say "amen."
Amen.
- Amen.
- We have
come here today
to celebrate the marvelous life
of Ms. Sylvia Lucille Hosannah.
- Oh, yeah.
- Born in Trinidad
on June the 8th
in the year 1957.
She is survived
by her beautiful children,
Princess Lee, Khadija Lee,
her son Steven Lee Jr.
and her grandchildren
Wesley and Zachary.
She was a passionate
childcare professional.
- Yes! Yes!
- Yes.
A nanny and nurse
to many, many children
right here in New York City.
And she always
loved children, eh?
But she didn't just take
care of children, right?
No.
Before settling down
and having children of her own,
she was a ballet dancer
with the Alvin Ailey
dance company in Harlem
for several years.
Yes.
Mixing Trinidadian
and traditional African dance,
she brought a confidence
and a freshness
to her rich and vibrant
dance milieu.
- Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
Sylvia was the first in her
family to move from Trinidad
to New York and always
sent money to her family.
She tried her best to get
all her brothers and sisters
to the U.S. as well.
- Including her sister Nancy,
whose son Oswald
is doing his thing
as wide receiver
for the Patriots!
Except last week.
Sad as he lost me
some money, boy.
Oswald James was
related to our nanny?
- Yeah, I heard.
- She will be
extremely missed.
God deals with death
as he knows it to be true.
Isaiah 41:10 says,
"Fear not, for I am with you.
- Yes.
"Be not dismayed,
- "for I am your God.
- Yes.
- "I will strengthen you.
- "I will help you.
- Yes.
"I will uphold you
with my righteous hand!
- Yes.
With my righteous hand."
Yes.
And she is upheld
with His righteous hand.
And she is with God,
sitting where?
- At the right...
- At the right hand
of the Father.
- May she rest in peace.
- What was that?
Uh, nothing. Nothing.
And may God bless
her sweet, sweet soul.
All right, that done.
Now, as per the deceased
Mrs. Hosannah's wishes,
we are asked
to celebrate her life.
I think one thing
we can all say about Sylvia,
is that she believed
in tradition...
...but she was
not at all traditional.
- This is true.
She asked that there
be limbo dance,
in tribute to Julia Edwards,
before being taken
to the burial site.
We have some students
and alumni here
from the Hillcrest High School
after-school dance program--
started by Sylvia, by the way--
to help us fulfill
this ask of Mrs. Hosannah.
We will also be playing
one of Sylvia's favorite songs,
- "Trini 2 De Bone."
- Yes!
So, if all you could please
join us in remembering Sylvia
in the way that she wanted
to be remembered.
Yes. Amen. Amen.
- There we go, now.
- All yah!
Stop all of this bacchanal.
Stop it!
- How-how she
reach up there?
- Here we go.
- Everyone here
- loved this woman.
- Princess!
I've heard about her sacrifices,
her selflessness,
but who do you think
she sacrificed, hmm?
To take care
of those children, hmm?
- She did the best
she could, Princess.
- Yeah?
Where was she
when we needed her, Steven?
Where was she when you got
jumped uptown,
and I couldn't find you
for a whole day?
Where was she
when they broke into our house
and stole my laptop?
Where was she?
Where was she
at your finals, Steven?
She was providing for us.
She was with other people's
children.
She should've been
taking care of her own!
That's enough, Princess. Stop.
I needed you, Mommy.
And where were you?!
Where were you?! Huh, Mama?!
You've always been crazy,
Princess!
Hey, but what you
really doing here?
- A'A?
Whoa.
It's a church! Stop!
I'm coming with you!
Stop it! Stop!
Worldstar! Worldstar!
There's a fight going down...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! Hey!
Hey! You all need
to calm down right now!
Look, you're scaring
the white people.
Uh... No, no, no, no.
No, uh...
We just have to go.
Hey, small man.
Are we scaring you?
It's okay.
We're just sad.
This... is how we're sad.
- You okay, Bash?
- Yes.
Well, if you want to sleep
with us, you can.
I'm okay.
Okay. All right.
Well...
Well, good night.
I love you.
Good night. I love you, Dad.
Good night, Sylvia.
Wow.
Oh, my gosh.
Hey, hon, you know the origin
of the limbo dance?
It's fascinating.
I mean, apparently,
slaves would do it to mimic
going down in the hold
- of a slave ship.
- Did we do the right thing?
What?
Of course we did.
Well, I just...
I mean, people were screaming.
- And-and the way that
that woman was yelling...
- All right, that...
...at her mother.
I just, I never... want
Sebastian to feel that way.
- Like we weren't there for him.
- No.
We were there for him today,
when he needed us.
We were there for him.
We are there for him.
Look, I know Sebastian,
and I know
that he can handle
what he saw today.
I know he'll be fine.
You know, when I was putting
Sebastian to bed tonight,
I asked him, "What do you want
to be when you grow up?"
and he said, "I want to play
steelpan like Uncle Samuel."
I don't even...
Honey, wha... U-Uncle Samuel?
I don't know what that is.
Who's Uncle Samuel?
- I don't know.
- Was he there today?
I don't know.